A Guide to the Virginia Secretary of the Commonwealth correspondence, 1891-1911
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Virginia Secretary of the Commonwealth correspondence, 1891-1911
The Library of Virginia
38174
12.35 cu. ft. (13 boxes)
Virginia. Office of the Secretary of the Commonwealth.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Transfer information is unavailable. Accessioned 6 June 2001.
Historical Information
The Office of the Secretary of the Commonwealth evolved from the position of the Secretary of the Colony during colonial times. Thomas Nelson held the position of the first Secretary of Virginia in 1776. Early Secretaries were elected by the public. An Act of the General Assembly in 1920 changed the election to a joint vote of the General Assembly. In a 1930 act of the General Assembly, the duties of the Secretary were redefined with the Secretary of the Commonwealth serving as the ex officio secretary of the Governor, as custodian of many official State records, and as keeper of the Greater and Lesser Seals of the Commonwealth. The office of the Secretary has gradually acquired other functions, such as: service of out-of-state civil process; appointment and regulation of notaries public; and registration and oversight of lobbyists. The Office became a gubernational appointment subsequent to a 1958 Act of the Assembly. The Secretary of the Commonwealth is under the jurisdiction of the Governor's Office and is appointed by the Governor for a term of four years.
Scope and Content
Contains incoming and outgoing correspondence of the Virginia Office of the Secretary of the Commonwealth during the tenure of Secretaries J.T. Lawless and D.Q. Eggleston. Also included are letters to and from the clerk of the Secretary of the Commonwealth, J.G. Hankins.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged into the following series:
Series I. Secretary's Correspondence, 1894-1909
Series II. Clerk's Correspondence, 1891-1911
Contents List
- Series I. Secretary's Correspondence, 1894-1909., Extent: 10.15 cu. ft.
  Contains the official correspondence of the Secretary of the Commonwealth. This series is divided into two subseries: General Correspondence and Subject Correspondence.
  - Subseries I. General Correspondence, 1897-1909., Extent: 7.5 cu. ft. (Box 1-8.)
    Contains requests for copies of state publications, business incorporation information, charters, and letters regarding various law-related topics.
    Arranged alphabetically by sender or recipient's last name and then chronologically within.
    - A, 1900. (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - A, 1901. (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - A, 1902. (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - A, 1903. (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - A, 1904. (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - A, 1904. (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - A, 1905. (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - A, 1905. (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - A, 1906. (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - A, 1906. (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - A, 1907. (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - A, 1908-1909. (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - B, 1900. (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - B, 1901. (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - B, 1902. (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - B, 1902. (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - B, 1903. (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - B, 1903. (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - B, 1904. (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - B, 1904. (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - B, 1904. (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - B, 1905. (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - B, 1905. (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - B, 1905. (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - B, 1905. (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - B, 1906. (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - B, 1906. (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - B, 1906. (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - B, 1907. (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - B, 1907. (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - B, 1908. (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - C, 1900-1902. (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - C, 1903. (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - C, 1904. (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - C, 1904. (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - C, 1904. (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - C, 1905. (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - C, 1905. (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - C, 1906. (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - C, 1906. (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - C, 1907. (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - C, 1907. (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - C, 1908-1909. (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - D, 1900. (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - D, 1901. (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - D, 1902. (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - D, 1903. (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - D, 1904. (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - D, 1905. (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - D, 1906. (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - D, 1907. (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - D, 1909. (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - E, 1900. (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - E, 1901. (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - E, 1902. (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - E, 1903. (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - E, 1904. (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - E, 1905. (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - E, 1906. (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - E, 1907-1909. (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - F, 1898-1900. (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - F, 1901. (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - F, 1902. (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - F, 1903. (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - F, 1904. (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - F, 1905. (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - F, 1906. (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - F, 1907-1909. (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - G, 1900. (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - G, 1901. (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - G, 1902. (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - G, 1903. (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - G, 1904. (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - G, 1904. (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - G, 1905. (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - G, 1906. (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - G, 1907. (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - G, 1908-1909. (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - H, 1900. (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - H, 1901. (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - H, 1902. (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - H, 1902. (Box 3, Folder 24)
    - H, 1903. (Box 3, Folder 25)
    - H, 1903. (Box 3, Folder 26)
    - H, 1904. (Box 3, Folder 27)
    - H, 1904. (Box 3, Folder 28)
    - H, 1905. (Box 3, Folder 29)
    - H, 1905. (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - H, 1905. (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - H, 1906. (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - H, 1906. (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - H, 1906. (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - H, 1907. (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - H, 1907. (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - H, 1908. (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - H, 1909. (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - I, 1900-1901. (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - I, 1902. (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - I, 1903-1904. (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - I, 1905-1907. (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - J, 1900-1901. (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - J, 1902. (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - J, 1903. (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - J, 1904. (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - J, 1905. (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - J, 1906. (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - J, 1907-1908. (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - K, 1900. (Box 4, Folder 21)
    - K, 1901. (Box 4, Folder 22)
    - K, 1902. (Box 4, Folder 23)
    - K, 1903. (Box 4, Folder 24)
    - K, 1904. (Box 4, Folder 25)
    - K, 1905. (Box 4, Folder 26)
    - K, 1906. (Box 4, Folder 27)
    - K, 1907. (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - K, 1908-1909. (Box 4, Folder 29)
    - L, 1900. (Box 4, Folder 30)
    - L, 1901. (Box 4, Folder 31)
    - L, 1902. (Box 4, Folder 32)
    - L, 1903. (Box 4, Folder 33)
    - L, 1904. (Box 4, Folder 34)
    - L, 1905. (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - L, 1906. (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - L, 1907. (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - L, 1908. (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - M, 1900. (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - M, 1901. (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - M, 1901. (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - M, 1902. (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - M, 1902. (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - M, 1902. (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - M, 1903. (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - M, 1903. (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - M, 1903. (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - M, 1904. (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - M, 1904. (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - M, 1904. (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - M, 1905. (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - M, 1905. (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - M, 1905. (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - M, 1905. (Box 5, Folder 20)
    - M, 1906. (Box 5, Folder 21)
    - M, 1906. (Box 5, Folder 22)
    - M, 1906. (Box 5, Folder 23)
    - M, 1907. (Box 5, Folder 24)
    - M, 1907. (Box 5, Folder 25)
    - M, 1908-1909. (Box 5, Folder 26)
    - N, 1900. (Box 5, Folder 27)
    - N, 1901. (Box 5, Folder 28)
    - N, 1902. (Box 5, Folder 29)
    - N, 1903. (Box 5, Folder 30)
    - N, 1904. (Box 5, Folder 31)
    - N, 1905. (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - N, 1906. (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - N, 1907. (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - N, 1908. (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - O, 1897-1900. (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - O, 1901. (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - O, 1902. (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - O, 1903. (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - O, 1904. (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - O, 1905. (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - O, 1906. (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - O, 1907. (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - P, 1900. (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - P, 1901. (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - P, 1902. (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - P, 1902. (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - P, 1903. (Box 6, Folder 17)
    - P, 1903. (Box 6, Folder 18)
    - P, 1904. (Box 6, Folder 19)
    - P, 1904. (Box 6, Folder 20)
    - P, 1905. (Box 6, Folder 21)
    - P, 1905. (Box 6, Folder 22)
    - P, 1906. (Box 6, Folder 23)
    - P, 1906. (Box 6, Folder 24)
    - P, 1907. (Box 6, Folder 25)
    - P, 1909. (Box 6, Folder 26)
    - Q, 1900-1908. (Box 6, Folder 27)
    - R, 1900. (Box 6, Folder 28)
    - R, 1901. (Box 6, Folder 29)
    - R, 1902. (Box 6, Folder 30)
    - R, 1903. (Box 6, Folder 31)
    - R, 1904. (Box 6, Folder 32)
    - R, 1905. (Box 6, Folder 33)
    - R, 1906. (Box 6, Folder 34)
    - R, 1907. (Box 6, Folder 35)
    - R, 1908-1909. (Box 6, Folder 36)
    - S, 1900. (Box 6, Folder 37)
    - S, 1901. (Box 6, Folder 38)
    - S, 1902. (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - S, 1903. (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - S, 1903. (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - S, 1904. (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - S, 1904. (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - S, 1905. (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - S, 1905. (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - S, 1905. (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - S, 1905. (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - S, 1906. (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - S, 1906. (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - S, 1906. (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - S, 1907. (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - S, 1907. (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - S, 1908. (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - S, 1909. (Box 7, Folder 16)
    - T, 1903. (Box 7, Folder 17)
    - T, 1904. (Box 7, Folder 18)
    - T, 1905. (Box 7, Folder 19)
    - T, 1905. (Box 7, Folder 20)
    - T, 1906. (Box 7, Folder 21)
    - T, 1906. (Box 7, Folder 22)
    - T, 1907. (Box 7, Folder 23)
    - T, 1908-1909. (Box 7, Folder 24)
    - U, 1903-1904. (Box 7, Folder 25)
    - U, 1905. (Box 7, Folder 26)
    - U, 1906. (Box 7, Folder 27)
    - U, 1907. (Box 7, Folder 28)
    - V, 1903-1904. (Box 7, Folder 29)
    - V, 1905. (Box 7, Folder 30)
    - V, 1906. (Box 7, Folder 31)
    - V, 1907. (Box 7, Folder 32)
    - V, 1908. (Box 7, Folder 33)
    - W, 1900. (Box 7, Folder 34)
    - W, 1901. (Box 7, Folder 35)
    - W, 1901. (Box 7, Folder 36)
    - W, 1902. (Box 7, Folder 37)
    - W, 1902. (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - W, 1902. (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - W, 1903. (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - W, 1903. (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - W, 1903. (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - W, 1904. (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - W, 1904. (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - W, 1904. (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - W, 1905. (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - W, 1905. (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - W, 1905. (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - W, 1906. (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - W, 1906. (Box 8, Folder 13)
    - W, 1906. (Box 8, Folder 14)
    - W, 1907. (Box 8, Folder 15)
    - W, 1908-1909. (Box 8, Folder 16)
    - Y, 1900-1902. (Box 8, Folder 17)
    - Y, 1903-1907. (Box 8, Folder 18)
    - Z, 1900-1907. (Box 8, Folder 19)
    - Miscellaneous, 1901; undated. (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - Subseries II. Subject Correspondence, 1894-1907., Extent: 2.65 cu. ft. (Box 8-11.)
    Contains letters to and from the Secretary of the Commonwealth which were grouped according to common topics such as automobile matters, appointments (the letters were originally addressed to Governor Andrew J. Montague), pardon requests (also addressed to Governor Montague), and notices of candidacy.
    Arranged alphabetically and then chronologically within.
    - Automobiles: A, 1906. (Box 8, Folder 21)
    - Automobiles: A, 1907. (Box 8, Folder 22)
    - Automobiles: B, 1906. (Box 8, Folder 23)
    - Automobiles: B, 1907. (Box 8, Folder 24)
    - Automobiles: C, 1906. (Box 8, Folder 25)
    - Automobiles: C, 1907. (Box 8, Folder 26)
    - Automobiles: D, 1906. (Box 8, Folder 27)
    - Automobiles: D, 1907. (Box 8, Folder 28)
    - Automobiles: E, 1906-1907. (Box 8, Folder 29)
    - Automobiles: F, 1906-1907. (Box 8, Folder 30)
    - Automobiles: G, 1906. (Box 8, Folder 31)
    - Automobiles: G, 1907. (Box 8, Folder 32)
    - Automobiles: H, 1906. (Box 8, Folder 33)
    - Automobiles: H, 1907. (Box 8, Folder 34)
    - Automobiles: I, 1907. (Box 8, Folder 35)
    - Automobiles: J, 1906-1907. (Box 8, Folder 36)
    - Automobiles: K, 1906-1907. (Box 8, Folder 37)
    - Automobiles: L, 1906-1907. (Box 8, Folder 38)
    - Automobiles: M, 1906. (Box 8, Folder 39)
    - Automobiles: M, 1907. (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Automobiles: N, 1906-1907. (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Automobiles: O, 1906. (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Automobiles: P, 1906. (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Automobiles: P, 1907. (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Automobiles: R, 1906. (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Automobiles: R, 1907. (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - Automobiles: S, 1906. (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - Automobiles: S, 1907. (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - Automobiles: T, 1906-1907. (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - Automobiles: U, 1906-1907. (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - Automobiles: V, 1906-1907. (Box 9, Folder 12)
    - Automobiles: W, 1906. (Box 9, Folder 13)
    - Automobiles: W, 1907. (Box 9, Folder 14)
    - Automobiles: Y, 1906-1907. (Box 9, Folder 15)
    - Automobiles: Z, 1906-1907. (Box 9, Folder 16)
    - Automobiles: City and County Laws (Automobile Act), 1906-1907. (Box 9, Folder 17)
    - Boards: Board of Agriculture, 1902. (Box 9, Folder 18)
    - Boards: Board of Medical Examiners, 1901. (Box 9, Folder 19)
    - Boards: Board of Pharmacy, 1902. (Box 9, Folder 20)
    - Boards: Central State Hospital (Board of Directors), 1901-1902. (Box 9, Folder 21)
    - Boards: College of William and Mary (Board of Visitors), 1903. (Box 9, Folder 22)
    - Boards: Eastern State Hospital (Board of Directors), 1903. (Box 9, Folder 23)
    - Boards: Institution for the Deaf and Dumb and for the Blind (Board of Visitors), 1901-1902. (Box 9, Folder 24)
    - Boards: Mount Vernon (Board of Visitors), 1902. (Box 9, Folder 25)
    - Boards: Normal School, Farmville (Board of Visitors), 1902. (Box 9, Folder 26)
    - Boards: Normal School, Petersburg (Board of Visitors), 1901-1902. (Box 9, Folder 27)
    - Boards: Penitentiary Board, 1903. (Box 9, Folder 28)
    - Boards: Southwestern State Hospital (Board of Directors), 1902-1903. (Box 9, Folder 29)
    - Boards: Southwestern State Hospital (Board of Directors), 1902-1903. (Box 9, Folder 30)
    - Boards: Southwestern State Hospital (Board of Directors), 1902-1903. (Box 9, Folder 31)
    - Boards: State Hospitals and Institution for the Deaf and Dumb and of the Blind, 1902. (Box 9, Folder 32)
    - Boards: University of Virginia (Board of Visitors), 1901-1902. (Box 9, Folder 33)
    - Boards: Virginia Military Institute (Board of Visitors), 1902. (Box 9, Folder 34)
    - Boards: Virginia Polytechnic Institute (Board of Visitors), 1901-1902. (Box 9, Folder 35)
    - Boards: Ter-Centennial Committee, 1902. (Box 9, Folder 36)
    - Boards: Western State Hospital (Board of Directors), 1901-1903. (Box 9, Folder 37)
    - Boards: Unspecified, 1901-1902. (Box 9, Folder 38)
    - Elections: Attorney General opinions, 1896. (Box 9, Folder 39)
    - Elections: Attorney General opinions, 1897. (Box 9, Folder 40)
    - Elections: Candidates for Congress (notices), 1894. (Box 9, Folder 41)
    - Elections: Candidates for Congress (notices), 1894. (Box 9, Folder 42)
    - Elections: Candidates for Congress (notices), 1896. (Box 9, Folder 43)
    - Elections: Candidates for Congress (offical notices sent to Secretary of the Electoral Board from Secretary of the Commonwealth), 1896. (Box 9, Folder 44)
    - Elections: Candidates for Congress (notices), 1898. (Box 9, Folder 45)
    - Elections: Candidates for Congress (notices), 1898. (Box 9, Folder 46)
    - Elections: Candidates for Congress (notices), 1898. (Box 9, Folder 47)
    - Elections: Candidates for Congress (notices), 1899. (Box 9, Folder 48)
    - Elections: Candidates for Congress (notices), 1900. (Box 9, Folder 49)
    - Elections: Candidates for Congress (official notices sent to Secretary of the Electoral Board from Secretary of the Commonwealth), 1902. (Box 9, Folder 50)
    - Elections: Candidates for Governor, Lt. Governor and Attorney General, 1897. (Box 9, Folder 51)
    - Elections: List of electors (various political parties), year. (Box 9, Folder 52)
    - Elections: List of electors (Electoral College), 1896. (Box 9, Folder 53)
    - Elections: Memorandum from the Secretary, 1896-1897. (Box 9, Folder 54)
    - Elections: Receipts of notification, 1894. (Box 9, Folder 55)
    - Jamestown Exposition: Commissioner appointment, undated. (Box 9, Folder 56)
    - Pardons: A, 1903-1905. (Box 9, Folder 57)
    - Pardons: B, 1901-1905. (Box 9, Folder 58)
    - Pardons: C, 1902-1905. (Box 9, Folder 59)
    - Pardons: D, 1902-1905. (Box 9, Folder 60)
    - Pardons: E, 1904-1905. (Box 9, Folder 61)
    - Pardons: F, 1903-1905. (Box 9, Folder 62)
    - Pardons: G, 1902-1903. (Box 9, Folder 63)
    - Pardons: H, 1902-1905. (Box 9, Folder 64)
    - Pardons: J, 1901-1905. (Box 9, Folder 65)
    - Pardons: K, 1903. (Box 9, Folder 66)
    - Pardons: L, 1902-1905. (Box 9, Folder 67)
    - Pardons: M, 1902-1905. (Box 9, Folder 68)
    - Pardons: N-O, 1902-1905. (Box 9, Folder 69)
    - Pardons: P, 1902-1906. (Box 9, Folder 70)
    - Pardons: R, 1903-1904. (Box 9, Folder 71)
    - Pardons: S, 1902-1904. (Box 9, Folder 72)
    - Pardons: T, 1902-1904. (Box 9, Folder 73)
    - Pardons: V-Y, 1900-1905. (Box 9, Folder 74)
    - State Board of Education: Appointments, E-J, 1903. (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - State Board of Education: Appointments, R-W, 1903. (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - State Board of Education: Miscellaneous, 1904. (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - State Corporation Commission: Appointments, A, 1902. (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - State Corporation Commission: Appointments, B, 1902. (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - State Corporation Commission: Appointments, B, 1902. (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - State Corporation Commission: Appointments, C, 1902. (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - State Corporation Commission: Appointments, D, 1902. (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - State Corporation Commission: Appointments, F, 1902. (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - State Corporation Commission: Appointments, G, 1902. (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - State Corporation Commission: Appointments, Goodman, E.S., 1902. (Box 10, Folder 11)
    - State Corporation Commission: Appointments, Goodman, E.S., 1902. (Box 10, Folder 12)
    - State Corporation Commission: Appointments, Goodman, E.S., 1902. (Box 10, Folder 13)
    - State Corporation Commission: Appointments, Goodman, E.S., 1902. (Box 10, Folder 14)
    - State Corporation Commission: Appointments, H, 1902. (Box 10, Folder 15)
    - State Corporation Commission: Appointments, K-L, 1902. (Box 10, Folder 16)
    - State Corporation Commission: Appointments, M, 1902. (Box 10, Folder 17)
    - State Corporation Commission: Appointments, O, 1902. (Box 10, Folder 18)
    - State Corporation Commission: Appointments, P, 1902. (Box 10, Folder 19)
    - State Corporation Commission: Appointments, S, 1902. (Box 10, Folder 20)
    - State Corporation Commission: Appointments, S, 1902. (Box 10, Folder 21)
    - State Corporation Commission: Appointments, T, 1902. (Box 10, Folder 22)
    - State Corporation Commission: Appointments, W, 1902. (Box 10, Folder 23)
    - St. Louis Exposition, 1902-1903. (Box 10, Folder 24)
    - Superintendents of Public Schools: Appointments, Albemarle, 1905. (Box 10, Folder 25)
    - Superintendents of Public Schools: Appointments, Alexandria, 1905. (Box 10, Folder 26)
    - Superintendents of Public Schools: Appointments, Alleghany, 1905. (Box 10, Folder 27)
    - Superintendents of Public Schools: Appointments, Amelia, 1905. (Box 10, Folder 28)
    - Superintendents of Public Schools: Appointments, Amherst, 1905. (Box 10, Folder 29)
    - Superintendents of Public Schools: Appointments, Augusta, 1905. (Box 10, Folder 30)
    - Superintendents of Public Schools: Appointments, Bath, 1905. (Box 10, Folder 31)
    - Superintendents of Public Schools: Appointments, Bedford, 1905. (Box 10, Folder 32)
    - Superintendents of Public Schools: Appointments, Bland, 1905. (Box 10, Folder 33)
    - Superintendents of Public Schools: Appointments, Botetourt/Brunswick/Buckingham, 1905. (Box 10, Folder 34)
    - Superintendents of Public Schools: Appointments, Campbell, 1905. (Box 10, Folder 35)
    - Superintendents of Public Schools: Appointments, Carroll, 1905. (Box 10, Folder 36)
    - Superintendents of Public Schools: Appointments, Charlotte/Clarke, 1905. (Box 10, Folder 37)
    - Superintendents of Public Schools: Appointments, Craig/Culpeper, 1905. (Box 10, Folder 38)
    - Superintendents of Public Schools: Appointments, Danville, 1905. (Box 10, Folder 39)
    - Superintendents of Public Schools: Appointments, Dickenson/Dinwiddie/Essex, 1905. (Box 10, Folder 40)
    - Superintendents of Public Schools: Appointments, Fauquier/Floyd, 1905. (Box 10, Folder 41)
    - Superintendents of Public Schools: Appointments, Fluvanna, 1904-1905. (Box 10, Folder 42)
    - Superintendents of Public Schools: Appointments, Giles/Gloucester/Goochland, 1904-1905. (Box 10, Folder 43)
    - Superintendents of Public Schools: Appointments, Hanover, 1905. (Box 10, Folder 44)
    - Superintendents of Public Schools: Appointments, Halifax, 1905. (Box 10, Folder 45)
    - Superintendents of Public Schools: Appointments, Henrico/Highland, 1905. (Box 10, Folder 46)
    - Superintendents of Public Schools: Appointments, King and Queen/King William, 1904-1905. (Box 10, Folder 47)
    - Superintendents of Public Schools: Appointments, Lancaster, 1905. (Box 10, Folder 48)
    - Superintendents of Public Schools: Appointments, Lee, 1905. (Box 10, Folder 49)
    - Superintendents of Public Schools: Appointments, Madison/Mecklenburg, 1905. (Box 10, Folder 50)
    - Superintendents of Public Schools: Appointments, Nelson/Newport News/Norfolk, 1905. (Box 10, Folder 51)
    - Superintendents of Public Schools: Appointments, Northampton/Orange, 1905. (Box 10, Folder 52)
    - Superintendents of Public Schools: Appointments, Patrick, 1905. (Box 10, Folder 53)
    - Superintendents of Public Schools: Appointments, Powhatan/Prince Edward, 1905. (Box 10, Folder 54)
    - Superintendents of Public Schools: Appointments, Pulaski, 1905. (Box 10, Folder 55)
    - Superintendents of Public Schools: Appointments, Roanoke, 1905. (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Superintendents of Public Schools: Appointments, Rockbridge/Russell, 1904-1905. (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Superintendents of Public Schools: Appointments, Shenandoah, 1905. (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Superintendents of Public Schools: Appointments, Southampton/Spotsylvania, 1905. (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - Superintendents of Public Schools: Appointments, Surry/Sussex, 1905. (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Superintendents of Public Schools: Appointments, Tazewell/Warren, 1905. (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - Superintendents of Public Schools: Appointments, Washington, 1905. (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - Superintendents of Public Schools: Appointments, Williamsburg/Wise, 1904-1905. (Box 11, Folder 8)
- Series II. Clerk's Correspondence, 1891-1911., Extent: 2.2 cu. ft.
  Contains the official and personal correspondence of the clerk to the Secretary of the Commonwealth, J.G. Hankins. Mr. Hankins served as clerk or in some capacity in the office of the secretary under Secretaries of the Commonwealth H.W. Flournoy, J.T. Lawless, and D.Q Eggleston. This series is divided into two subseries: General Correspondence and Subject Correspondence.
  - Subseries I. General Correspondence, 1891-1911., Extent: 1.7 cu. ft. (Box 11-12)